I felt really happy.
非常的开心
Everything went smoothly.
嗯一切都很顺利
I had a pretty good day today.
今天过得挺愉快的
So, my schedule is back to normal
所以作息时间又正常
Actually, this is when I feel the most tired and sleepy
其实现在是我最困最累的时候
When I decided to come out and record a video
当我决定还出来录像
I want to talk about changing one's destiny
我想讲一讲关于逆天改命的事情
Many people have been discussing how to change their destiny lately
其实很多人最近都在讲如何逆天改命
How should I put it
如何怎么说呢
Taking control of your own destiny
把握自己的命运
But I think they've made the issue too complicated
但是我觉得其实他把这个问题讲的太复杂了
Actually, destiny is a combination of your personality and habits
其实命运本身就是性格跟你的做事习惯
So, if you want to change your destiny,
所以你想改变命运来讲
in simple terms, it means going against your usual way of doing things, and that’s how you make a change.
说白了就是逆着你的做事习惯来明面就改了
That means when there’s something you don’t want to do,
也就是说你不想干什么事情时候
you should do it anyway.
你偏要去干什么事情
Sometimes, this can even change your name.
有的时候他就能改名
But the most crucial point is,
而最关键的一点
I believe in reading a thousand books and traveling a thousand miles.
我觉得读万卷书行万里路
Often, it’s not just about changing your perception,
很多的时候其实不完全是认知的改变啊
but about the process of changing your perception.
认知的改变来讲的话
After he made changes in his behavior it truly brings about a transformation in your life I think many things are hard to come by, like finding a true love but it’s quite simple for celebrities it comes from the other people you encounter in your life’s journey
他作为行为的改变之后 真正对你人生有改变来讲的话 我觉得很多东西是这个爱人是很难遇到的事情 但是艺人却很简单的事情 就是你来自于你命运中遇到的其他人
their reactions to you have changed
对你的反应产生了改变
meaning all sorts of opportunities that come your way
也就是说你命运当中的各种各样的机会
the reason they come into your life
之所以他会来到你的身边啊
is often due to something like WeChat
无非就就是在于比如微信
You saw a certain post in your social circle.
你看见了朋友圈的某条信息
Or your posts resonated with someone else.
或者你的朋友圈引起了别人
Someone who rarely talks to you found resonance.
某一个经常不跟你说话的人的共鸣
Or the state brought about by your interaction with someone.
或者你跟某个人的交流带来的某种状态
In other words, it's about changing one's fate through people.
就是说其实是通过人来改命的
Why do I need the little sister to add Weiwei?
为什么要小妹妹加薇薇
This is about mastering the random factors in destiny.
这就是在掌握命运的随机性因素
I mean, many things, when you think about it,
我说很多的事情其实来讲的话
If you look at life from the perspective of my age and experience,
如果你在我这个人生的这个长度来看的话
Some things make sense when you look at them in reverse.
有些东西倒过来推看起来就是合理的
For example, Teacher Rong is a real ladies' man.
比如说荣老师这个人非常的好色
When it comes to being a ladies' man,
好色呢本身来讲的话
the character for 'lust' has a knife above it,
色字头上一把刀
you end up paying a high price for lust. A price in terms of health, a price in terms of money, and a price in terms of life's journey. I've paid all these prices. But the most crucial point is if you have this inclination,
你会为色付出很多的代价 健康的代价 金钱的代价 人生的那个旅程的代价 这些东西代价呢我都付过 但是最重要的一点就是 如果你拥有这种倾向的话
you would be willing to interact extensively with the opposite sex in real life,
你就会愿意在现实生活中呢大量的接触异性
regardless of whether
而其实异性的时候
you are a woman,
无论是你是女生啊
the opposite sex is a man or a woman,
异性是男生还是男生
or the opposite sex is a woman,
异性是女生
they can provide you with a lot of support,
他都能给你给予大量的帮助
not just financially.
这不光是金钱上的
And emotional support as well
还有情感上的帮助
There's a lot to talk about
有很多东西来讲
Especially, the trigger of opportunities is crucial
特别是机会上的这种触发是非常重要的
I mean, most of my real-life opportunities
也就是说其实我现实中的大部分机会
I'd say 75% are due to
可以说75%都是由于啊
opportunities brought by friends of the opposite sex
异性的好友给我带来的
So, in many cases
所以很多的时候来讲
Being attractive isn't the goal
你的色不是目的
It's just the cause
它只是起因
But the final outcome may not be as you expect.
但是你最终达到的结果未必就是说啊
It doesn't mean you have to do something with everyone.
你要跟每一个人都怎么着
That's not the case.
不是这样
It's just a reason that motivates you to connect with others.
他只是一个你想去加别人的诱因啊
It's just a motive.
动机而已
But once you have this motive, you'll find that:
但是有了这个动机诱因以后呢
After getting to know these people,
你会发现认识了这些人以后
You do indeed want to meet others for this reason,
你确实因为这样的原因想去认识别人
But after meeting them, your relationships will evolve. Not everyone is inclined towards the romantic path. That direction. Most people, how should I put it, take the realistic route. They move towards realism.
但认识以后你这个关系就发生了变化 因为不是每个人都会往你往那个romantic 那个方向去走 更多人往那个怎么说呢 realistic的方向走 往这个现实主义的方向走
In other words, why do people want to be in relationships with each other?
也就是说其实人互相之间为什么之间想交往
It’s because there’s a mutual benefit to coordinate.
就是因为有一个利益协调
To support each other,
相互帮助啊
and enhance their ability to survive.
扩大这个生存能力的这个问题
People have been this way since ancient times.
就是人从古代开始就是这样
When you have skills that can help others,
你有一些技能能给别人提供帮助的时候
you can't just sit there.
你就不能啊
How should I put it?
怎么说呢
the one you love the most,
啊自己特别的爱人
you focus on your own affairs,
自己的特别的守着自己这点事
because skills are only exchanged through time,
因为技能只有交换时间交换
helping each other heal wounds,
互相帮助对方舔伤口
supporting each other
互相帮助对方
Provide what the other party needs
提供对方需要的东西
You can truly be of use
你才能真正啊有用
For example, I know how to use computers
比如说我会计算机
I speak English
我会英文啊
I know swordsmanship
我会这个剑术
I have many skills
我会很多东西
But if you don’t offer your services as a bodyguard
但你不给别人当保镖
Don’t escort people home
不送别人回家
Don’t fix computers for others
不给别人修电脑啊
Not teaching others English
不教别人英文
Not engaging in English conversations with others
不跟别人进行英文之类的交流
Wouldn't these skills be wasted then?
你这些技能不就等于白修了吗
So, in many cases What's most important is Not the specific skills you have now Nor is it the knowledge you possess But rather, the exchange that happens between people Why is it said that doing business
所以很多的时候来讲 最重要的讲 不是你现在拥有的某种技能 也不是你拥有某种认知 而是你要需要跟人的交换的过程中啊 为什么说做生意
Doing business involves a lot of exchanges with people.
做生意也是跟大量的人进行交换
In these exchanges, you provide goods and services.
在交换的过程中提供了商品跟服务
So ultimately, your fate changes as a result.
所以最终来讲你的命运发生了改变
Therefore, the way to change your fate is to meet more people.
所以说你改变命运的方式就是去认识更多的人
Meet more people.
认识更多的人
It's not just about adding them on WeChat.
不光是加到对方的微信
You also need to learn how to interact with more people.
你还要学会跟更多的人互动
Engage with those who resonate with you.
跟你有你有共鸣的人进行互动
That's why some people talk about mastering private domains.
所以为什么有些人说要玩转私域
Post more on your Moments
要多发朋友圈
Master the art of WeChat groups
要玩转微信群
Often
很多的时候
Your social activity level is often the ease with which you earn money
你的社交活跃度就是你挣钱的容易程度
When you create a vibrant and active social atmosphere
你创立了这种大型的社交的这种活跃的氛围
You gain access to a wealth of genuine information sources
你就掌握了大量的真正的信心来源
As a person
因为你作为一个人
On your journey through life
走在你这一条人生道路上
It's virtually impossible to gather all the information.
获得所有的信息的收集是不太可能的
There are only two methods for intelligence gathering.
情报的收集只有两种方式
One is through technical means.
一种就是用技术手段收集啊
You need to understand these technical methods.
技术手段你要懂技术手段
The scope of technical collection is quite broad. But you need to refine it. The other method is through personnel. Targeting key individuals in important areas. These targets possess specific intelligence information.
技术手段收集的范围是非常大的 但你需要给它精细化 还有一点就是人员收集 根据重要的某个方面的人员的目标 这个目标他掌握什么样的情报信息
You just need to engage with him in various emotional interactions.
你只需要跟他有各种各样的情感上的互动
That's why spies have to be exceptionally articulate and persuasive.
所以为什么说当间谍的人都得特别会能说会道
They need to know how to charm people.
得会泡妞才行
This is crucial.
这个东西是很重要的
Because it's about gathering information.
因为这是获情
The key to obtaining intelligence lies right here.
就是获取情报的最关键的地方就在于此
If you can't even gather the information,
如果你连情报都不能获取
How can you analyze it afterward?
你事后怎么样去分析
How can you make use of it?
怎么样去利用来讲
That's all talk.
那都是废话
That's all future talk.
那都是后话
That's something that can't exist.
那不可能存在的东西
So, at the beginning, no matter what,
所以一开始无论怎么样啊
A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step.
千里之行始于足下
At first, it was just a little girl named Weiwei.
一开始都是一个小妹妹加微微
Then, in a particularly shameless and excited manner,
然后一个特不要脸的一个特别激动的方式
Why use such a few methods to start high?
为什么要用这种几种的方式高开
Because your energy field is strong.
因为你的能量场比较强
Many people are afraid to say 'oh no'
很多人害怕说哎呀
What if they end up disliking me?
万一对方讨厌我怎么样
If they dislike you, they won’t add you
对方讨厌你就不会加你了
They simply won’t add you
对方就不会加你了
Right?
对不对
So the first challenge you’ll face is getting added by a young girl named Weiwei People who don’t have a bad feeling about you Or even those who have a good impression of you He will go through this kind of inspection. Otherwise, who would bother to check what you're up to? They would just not add you.
所以你这一关首先你挑战的就是小妹妹加微微 不反感你的人嗯 不反感你的人 甚至是对你有好感的人 他才会经过这方面的检验 否则一个人看你谁有操什么东西啊 就就直接不会加你了
After you add him, though,
你又加过他以后呢
there are these high-level energy aspects.
又有这些高层次的能量的东西
You don’t just say, ‘Hi, nice to meet you.’
你不是说呀你好认识一下啊
Let’s keep it up.
咱们加油以后
For easier communication,
为了方便联系
this is called low energy.
这叫低能量
What are high-energy things?
高能量的东西是什么呀
Oh, you actually added me!
啊你居然加我了
This time it got through.
这回通过了啊
I'm so happy about it.
这我好高兴
I'm so thrilled!
好开心哇
Really, it is?
居然是啊
How can I put it?
怎么说呢
This beauty is stunning.
这个这个这个颜值惊为天人
You're the one who brings this kind of energy out.
你就是这种能量出去来讲
While in most cases
虽然来讲你是很多的时候
you can quickly assess the type of person you're dealing with
你就能快速判断对方的类型
if they are particularly responsive
对方如果是那种回应力比较强的人
it suggests they have a higher IQ
说明他的智商比较高
but they might be emotionally unstable
情绪不稳定
if their responses are slower
如果他的回应比较慢来讲
they tend to be more self-protective
就是倾向于自我保护主义比较强一点
these people warm up slowly
这种人是慢热的
of course, there are also those who respond in a more polished manner
当然也有那种回应的比较圆滑
quite random
比较随机的
but for this kind of person
但是这种人来讲
the tendency for self-protection might not be particularly strong
自我保护的倾向来讲可能不是特别重
but he is also testing you
但是他呢也是在试探你
so in all the processes of testing each other
所以在所有的你在跟人试探的过程当中
you also learn how to interact with people
你也学会了如何与人交往
so the beloved one is not predestined it's not predestined that you suffer from your original family from a young age don't always criticize you You're always afraid of changes in your self-image it naturally turns into a relationship
所以这个艺人爱人不是天生注定的 他不是天生注定你从小挨着原生家庭的苦 多老是批判你 老是你害怕自我形象的改变 那就自然会变成爱人
If you receive positive feedback
如果你得到正面反馈
constantly refine and adjust
多不断的去修正
into a positive interaction with others
跟别人之间的互动的这种良性关系了
you become an artist
那你就变成艺人
Actually, being an artist doesn't mean you're entirely skilled at socializing
其实艺人不是说完完全全说我就擅长交际
or that you get immediate and intense satisfaction from socializing
或者说我能从交际中得到很快的很爽的东西
a lot of this is surface-level, relatively safe information
很多的表面上的这种比较安全的信息
Instead, I don't care if others bring me negative emotions.
而是我不在意别人是否给我带来负面的情绪
I don't really mind the matter itself.
这件事情本身不在意
Because I had a happy childhood.
因为我有一个快乐的童年
I lead a relatively complete and fulfilling life.
我过一个比较完整的比较
How should I put it?
怎么说呢
A positive feedback dynamic from my family of origin.
正向反馈的一个原生家庭的一个动力关系
A supportive environment.
动力环境
So I'm willing to communicate with others.
所以我就愿意跟别人交流
And I don't carry those negative feelings from interactions.
而且我不会把那些不好的交流的感觉
Carry it into my next relationship
带到我下一个关系当中来
So in fact, I'm quite honest
所以其实我实在的
My social life is always one-on-one with others
我的社交其实永远跟别人都是单线类
I don't really belong to any particular social circle
我不太属于某一个社交圈子啊
For example, we have a group of friends who go fishing together every day
比如说我们这有一圈朋友天天一块钓鱼
I have a group of friends who go to the internet cafe every day How about the Tianjin area I maintain a single line with whoever I am actually always one-on-one Through repeated one-on-one interactions I gradually learned how to counter each personality type each character trait
我一圈朋友天天去网吧 天津区怎么着 我属于单线跟谁 我其实都是单线的 所以在不停的多次的单线联系当中 我逐渐掌握了如何对抗每一种人格 每一种性格
each zodiac sign
每一种星座
each blood type
每一种血型
how you generally react
你大概是什么样的反应
which can reflect your family background
能代表你的家庭成长环境
what your family members do for a living
你的家里人是什么职业
what your personality is like
你是什么性格
What was your reaction?
你的反应是什么样的
What do you expect from me?
你对我的期望是什么
Do you have a good impression of me?
你是否对我有好感
Do you have any desire for me?
是否对我有欲望
I can know everything.
我全都能知道
So through these things,
所以通过这些东西
In the long run, it's like playing cards,
长期的这种就像打牌一样
After this long-term game-like relationship,
这种长期的博弈的关系以后
You will understand how to be superior to others.
你就能明白如何凌驾于他人
Or how you get what you want from others
或者说你如何从别人身上得到你想要的东西
Of course, that's a rather utilitarian way to put it
当然来讲这是比较功利的说法
More importantly, we talk about how to serve others
更多的来讲我们说如何服务他人
How to experience what a person is going through
如何为一个人体验到
Or to sense what they need most
或者说感受到他最想需要的是什么东西
This is what takes the relationship to a deeper psychological level
这才是走进深层次心理的一些更深一部分关系
Unlocking the option for a fully warm and welcoming connection
解锁这种特别百分之百的友好度的这种选项
A bond between souls
的这种灵魂之间的关系
Only then can you truly reach someone's heart If you approach someone with the intention of using them or just to spend a night together the other person will sense it so it's important to be honest with the intention of not deceiving the other person
你只有这样才能到达别人的心灵 如果你上来就是想利用别人 就是想跟别人睡一觉的话 别人也会感知到 所以就是要以不欺为妻啊 以不欺骗对方的目的
but in the end, you end up deceiving them
最后达到了欺骗对方的目的
so war is all about deception
所以war is deception
as the old saying goes, war is a matter of deceit
很多时候老讲兵者诡道也
it's precisely because you don't have such intentions that you can achieve your goal
你正是因为没有这样的目的才能达到目的
But once you have a goal in mind
但是你有了目的以后
the other person will sense your intention
对方会觉察你的目的
so interactions between people are mutual
所以人之间都是互动的
don’t treat others as fools
不要拿别人当傻子
and when it comes to human interactions
而且人与人之间的交往来讲
it’s not just a battle of intelligence
不光是智商的较量
it’s also a test of emotional intelligence
也有情商的较量
for many, it’s about the intangible feelings
很多人来讲是一种感受的东西
so that’s where psychology comes into play
所以你就说心理学
Especially individual psychology
特别是个体的心理
you need to have an accurate understanding
你要有一个准确的了解
especially game theory
特别是博弈论的东西
you also need to understand
你也要明白
so this is what truly benefits your business
所以这个东西才是真正对你生意
or positively impacts your life
或者说对你人生有正向改变的东西
it’s about interpersonal relationships
就是人际关系
if you get interpersonal relationships right
如果你把人际关系这个东西弄好了
the philosophy of gift-giving
送礼的哲学
This is just one aspect of it.
这也是其中的一个面相而已
If you truly manage relationships with men,
如果你真的把男性啊
both same-sex and opposite-sex relationships well,
同性异性的关系都处理好了
understand what others think and know,
把别人所想所知
and address what they need internally, and balance them well, then you will have effectively managed your relationship with clients, with the market, and with your superiors and subordinates. you'll be invincible so let me explain let me tell you instead of studying things in nature
然后他内心中所需要的东西处理好 协调好了 那你就等于处理好你跟客户的关系 跟市场的关系 还有跟上下级的关系 就能无往而不利 所以我来讲 我跟你说 与其去研究自然界的东西
studying humanities is more interesting
研究人文学科更有意思
because humanities help you understand your fellow humans
因为人文学科是帮助你了解你的同类的
your fellow humans are made up of individuals
你的同类是由一个一个人构成的
and what others have in their hands
而其他的人手头里边拥有的
are the resources you desire
你的资源是你想需要的
Because most of your resources
因为你大部分资源
aren't obtained through exchanges with nature
不是说你从大跟大自然之间的交换来的
but are taken from other members of your species
都是从其他的同类手里拿到的
If you want sexual resources
你想要性资源
at the very least, someone has to be willing to sleep with you
起码得别人愿意跟你睡觉吧
If you want to make money
你想赚钱
you at least have to offer something others want
你起码得提供别人想要的东西吧
so they can trade money with you
所以他才能用钱跟你交换
So this is the most crucial point
所以这个东西最重要的来讲
It motivates you to serve others.
是促使你如何去向其他的人类服务
To serve others effectively,
你想像其他的人类服务
you need to understand their needs.
你就得了解其他人类的需求
and their personality traits.
跟他的性格特征是什么
So, in different social settings,
所以在不同的与人环境
as you interact with people,
与人相往交往的过程中
you can learn these skills.
你才能学到这些东西
This will truly transform you into a competent salesperson.
才能真正让你变成一个合适的销售
and a suitable marketing professional.
才能真正让变成一个合适的一个市场
That’s what truly enables you to sell what you want to sell. These things are all about playing the game of relationships. The problems that can ultimately be resolved. So many people may not seem highly educated. But they succeed because they deeply understand the principles of business.
才能真正让你销售你想卖的东西 这些东西都是玩人际关系啊 最终能够解决出来的问题 所以很多人他看似学历并不高 但是他却因为深谙生意场的这些道理
They frequently interact with others.
经常跟人打交道
So it becomes their own business wisdom.
所以就变成了他自己的生意经
They might not have a high level of education or cultural knowledge.
他可能学历文化水平并不高
But they can still make a lot of money.
但他却能赚到大钱
This is the core reason
这就是其中的核心原因
But we have high education
但是我们学历很高
Many friends would say
很多朋友来讲
Often overlook this point
往往忽视这一点
Often put in the effort
往往用心啊
I am a lover
我是爱人
I am introverted
我内向
I don't like talking to people
我不愿意跟人说话
I have my own world
我有我自己的世界
And that's it
然后就这样
If you want to make money
你要想赚钱
Then you have to become an entertainer
那你就得变成艺人
It's that simple
就这么简单
Because being an entertainer is the simplest way
因为艺人是最简单的一种方法
Sometimes I don't like to label people as introverted or extroverted
我有时候不要把人翻成什么内向外向之类的
If you care about your own feelings
你如果在意自己的感受
Then you won't want to communicate with others
那你就不会想去跟别人交流
For a long time, I've said
我很长时间以来讲
I could be a very isolated person
我都能都达哥达的一个人
Completely cut off from the outside world
完全不与外界交流
But when I need to make money
但是当我需要赚钱
When I need to interact with the outside world
当我需要跟外界产生互动交换的时候
I have to become active
我就必须活跃起来
Otherwise, you won't even have a social life, right?
否则你连性关系都不会有对吧
If you have nothing
你什么都不会有的话
None of your needs will be met So we are all half willing and half reluctant I don't want to engage with others When it comes to communication I become an introverted and isolated state
你的什么东西都不会满足 所以来讲咱人都是半义半爱的 我不想跟别人发生关系 发生交流的时候 我就是一个内向自闭的状态
Of course, when I want to communicate with others
当然我想跟别人来讲交流
I become an open and active state
我就是一个开放活跃的状态
So it depends on the level of energy
所以就分能量的高与低
But don't let your family background
但是不要因为自己的原生家庭
Or other reasons
不要因为自己的其他原因
Lead you to label yourself
导致自己给自己贴了标签
You mustn't do that
一定不要这样
If you want to make money
所以你想赚钱
If you want to do business
你想做生意
If you want to achieve great things
你想做大件大事情
If you want to manage people
你想管理人
If you want to be above others
你想立于人之上
You must learn to understand your peers
必须要学会了熟悉你同类
These are things you can learn from humanities disciplines
这些东西是你学人文学科都能囊括到的